Resume

Rupert Luxton

Date of Birth: 26/05/1991

Address: 10/53 Spit Road

Mosman NSW 2088

Telephone: 0400 768 486

Email: rupertluxton@hotmail.com

Career Goal

As I am in the beginning phase of my career as a professional Planner, my primary goals are to learn as much as I can through performing to the best of my ability for my employer. I also recognise the importance of building a strong reputation for my self within the industry and establishing connections. Furthermore, I would like to gain experience in all avenues of Planning over my career before specialising in one particular area.

Employment History

Feb 2014 – Current

Chief Account Manager

Rank Media

Experience and skills developed

- Management of staff
- Management of finances
- Management of client relations
- Sales

Nov 2013 - Feb 2014

Town Planner

APP Corporation Pty Ltd

- Strong understanding of NSW planning system and legislation
- Preparation of Statutory and Strategic Planning Reports
- Verbal and written planning advice
- Attending meetings with clients and Councils

July 2012 – Nov 2013

Student Planner

Logan City Council

- Development Assessment
- Customer service
- Strategic Planning
- Strong understanding of local government politics
- Environmental Planning
- Formulation of Local Area Plans
- Strong understanding of QLD playing system and legislation

April 2011 – August 2012

Receptionist

Healthworks Gym Hendra, Hendra

- · Customer liaison, service and advice
- Administrative work
- Equipment cleaning

February 2010 – April 2011 **Teleservicer**

EO Financial Services, Toowong

- Customer liaison, service and advice
- Phone and conversation skills
- Dealing with a variety of people

Other Positions

2009 (Jan – Dec) Labour Solutions Australia (Labourer)

2008 (Jan – Dec) Windsor Road Pharmacy (Pharmacy Assistant)

Educational Background

2009 - 2013

Bachelor of Urban and Environmental Planning

Griffith University

Key Subjects

- · Environmental Planning
- Sustainable Development
- · Earth Science and GIS
- Planning Practice and Law
- Strategic Planning Studio
- Urban Design
- Development Processes Studio
- · Advanced Environmental and Planning Law
- · Transport Planning

2006 - 2008

High School

St Josephs Nudgee College, Brisbane

Professional Competencies

- Effective written communication skills: Developed through assignment and report writing at school, University and in the work place.
- **Verbal communication and negotiation skills:** Gained through social interaction, the workplace, books and seminars, travelling, social networking and email.
- **Graphics and design skills**: Acquired through undertaking design projects at university, Logan City Council and APP Corporation.
- **Highly- developed analytical and research skills**: Attained through University studies, working as a student planner and in my spare time.
- Ability to cope effectively under stress: Acquired through working 32 hours per week, whilst fulfilling full-time university and other commitments.
- **Strong customer focus:** Developed through previous roles placing a high emphasis on customer service.
- Excellent teamwork skills: Gained through group assignments, the workplace and team sports.
- Ability to communicate and work with a wide variety of people: Gained through diverse range of work experience and university assignments.

• Capable of handling multiple competing tasks and deadlines: Demonstrated through never having missed the deadline for an assessment item at University, or handed in a work related report or task late.

Self-Education and Personal Growth

I enjoy spending a large proportion of my time developing myself personally through reading books and attending seminars on communication, money management, goal setting, marketing and how to be successful in all facets of life. I believe that many of the skills acquired through these books and seminars are an asset to any organisation.

Computer Skills

- Microsoft Word
- Excel
- PowerPoint
- MS Project
- Geographical Information Systems courses including; ArcGIS and ArcMap, Easimaps, Nearmap
- Google SketchUp
- Pathway
- Easimaps
- Data Management Systems

Licences

- · Current Queensland Drivers Licence
- NSW WorkCover General Construction Induction Card

Sporting Achievements

- Queensland Athletics and Cross Country representative
- Nudgee College first 11 soccer representative

Overseas Travel

Travelling through South East Asia, Europe and South America has enabled me to develop many personal skills that are invaluable within the workplace. Moreover, travelling through these regions has enabled me to experience different planning systems first hand.

Referees

- Clare Brown NSW Principal Planner APP Corporation 0425 284 398
- Graham Kruger Senior IDAS Officer Logan City Council 07 3412 5279
- Robyn Griffin Planning Officer Logan City Council 07 3412 5269

Letter of Recommendation

Please see following page.



Graham Kruger
Senior IDAS Officer – Development Assessment Branch
Logan City Council
Phone: 3412 5279
grahamkruger@logan.qld.gov.au

150 Wembley Road Logan Central QLD 4114 PO Box 3226 Logan City DC QLD 4114

Council enquiries 07 3412 3412
Council fax 07 3412 3444
Email council@logan.qld.gov.au
Web www.logan.qld.gov.au
ABN 21 627 796 435

16 August 2013

Dear Sir/Madam

RE: LETTER OF RECOMMENDATION FOR RUPERT LUXTON

Rupert has been working with Logan City Council for a period of 14 months as a Student Planner in the Development Assessment Branch. In which, I have been responsible for the supervision of Rupert over this time.

It has been a pleasure to work with Rupert due to his genuine enthusiasm, passion for quality customer service and strong understanding of technical planning matters. Overall, Rupert has demonstrated the following skills and abilities:

- Exceptional work ethic
- Ability to work with a range of individuals within a team environment
- Exceptional written and verbal communication skills
- Strong understanding of IDAS and statutory planning legislation
- Ability to indentify practical solutions to complex land use planning issues
- Ability to develop constructive relationships with internal and external stakeholders
- Ability to work autonomously
- Strong organisational and problem solving capabilities
- Ability to facilitate team meetings
- Understanding of strategic land use planning objectives
- Strong understanding of pre-lodgement meeting processes

I would be more than happy to support Rupert for any prospective job opportunities he may apply for. In addition, I believe Rupert would be a valuable asset for any future employer.

Please do not hesitate to contact me to discuss this letter of recommendation.

Yours faithfully

Graham Kruger

Senior IDAS Officer - Development Assessment Branch



